So, hello.
Welcome back to the latent space for a very packed session with Emma Burrows.
Emma is going to be talking about how to build a product brain
that becomes an agent orchestrator.
Yeah, sorry, I had to check
because the title has changed, but this sounds very exciting.
So a little bit about Emma.
Emma, as I mentioned, worked at Rezonant and she used to be the CTO
at Stripe in the UK.
So I'm going to hand over to her now,
if I should, to meet you.
Emma.
Thank you very much.
All right.
So I'm going to talk today about how to build your own product.
Brain so Rezonant for a little bit of context, is a product workspace
for helping people write specs, produce tasks, etc.
and then ship them very fast.
But what we have realized in the process of building out this product
is that PMS role fundamentally needs to change and accelerate
even faster than the kind of tools that we have built already accommodate.
So that's what we're going to talk about today, is how you can build a
reinforcement learning system that learns your product instincts
so that as a product manager, you can focus on the things that really matter,
which is the strategy of your company, and keep up with your engineers.
So a little bit about me.
Before founding Rezonant, as our host mentioned,
I was at Stripe for four years running engineering in the UK,
but I have always spent a bunch of time between basically product and engineering.
I started my career as a PM at Google, and then I ran product engineering
and design at an e-commerce company, so have really enjoyed this kind of fix
the last six months, where things have changed
dramatically in terms of the expectations of both engineers
and PMS, and thinking about where this is all going.
So coding is is solved sort of kind of a little bit at least.
And PM is next.
And what I mean by this is we have kind of really focused on this problem
of how we can accelerate code with the process of agents,
but nobody has really caught up from our product management perspective.
And so if you speak to a bunch of kind of CTOs and CPOs,
what tends to happen is product managers then get pulled down into the day to day.
Their engineers are moving so much faster as a consequence
of agent coding that now this core question of like,
what do you build and how do you build it tastefully has become much more key.
And at the moment, where most PMS are, is trying to just kind of do
workflows, basic workflows that help them do their day to day
job, you know, break this down into tickets.
Resonant also does all of these things very well,
for what it's worth, but I think where we need to go is towards
what software engineers has have become, which is agent orchestrators.
So we identify the slices of product management work
that can actually actually be done autonomously, end to end.
And in order to do that,
you need a system that kind of learns and understands your product.
So most of are here, they're using ChatGPT etc.
to help them do these workflows.
Then they're starting to
actually orchestrate a set of skills to help them run those workflows.
And then where I think we need to get to is actually having agents that have
a sense of taste, coherency, but also understand their own limitations.
Software engineering from a
product perspective, has also already gone through this right.
If you think about what cursor did, it was very much like line by line assistance
when it started out with C, cursor has become more than that over time.
Then we went really kind of deep on Claude code, and now there's the OpenClaw.
If you're brave enough from a kind of permissions perspective
to run those agents end to end,
but for the actual automation process is harder, right?
You have a much less consistent set of work and training data
to optimize this on.
So you need to automate your process of gathering information from your customers,
from your slack conversations, from your emails.
You need to work out what your human agent control plane is.
How are you going to ensure that you have the right checks and balances
between your agents and your PM so that they can work effectively?
And for that, we've built a kind of product brain to help us do that.
We've then deployed that with a number of design partners as well,
and now we're trying to backport it into into Rezonant over time also.
But it consists of a number of kind of key features.
So I'm going to run through kind of how it works.
And then I'll give you a bit of a demo end to end.
So the first thing is live ingestion.
So any time you have a meeting with a customer, for example, in granola,
you should automatically be able to process that information
and update your product.
Understanding GitHub itself is a valuable source of like
where is your product today?
What does it do?
Things like email, for example, linear tickets, etc.
all need to be ingested automatically because if the system isn't up to date,
you can't really run autonomous workflows.
Then you have your actual product brain, which needs to synthesize
all of these inputs into a form that can be quickly processed
by any agents that are running autonomously.
And finally, you need to configure a bunch of workflows on top of it.
Maybe when a customer ticket comes in, you want to be
able to go back to the customer if their ticket is unclear.
Equally, maybe if it is
well specked, you want to be able to ship that end to end really quickly.
All of this is very much a personal taste thing that companies need to grapple
with and work out how they want to express their level of autonomy over time.
But finally, the most important piece is you need some kind of human input
so that the system can reinforce its learning loop and get better over time.
Understanding how you think about product.
Okay, I think I probably
actually talked through most of this live ingestion as this process of input.
We'll see that in a second.
This is a kind of graph of our product brain.
It builds a bunch of links between
the different concepts being discussed at a bunch of different levels.
And then we can figure workflows on top of it,
which are completely customized to our kind of end to end process.
And we have a set of agents to do this.
The first is an action agent, pretty obvious.
It runs the workflows.
We have an input and a brain agent
whose function is to process those inputs and reorganize them.
And then we also have an organizational agent.
So over time your wiki gets out of date.
It needs to be reorganized.
Also, teams reorganized one selves as well.
And so you need a way to kind of organize around
company organizations, teams and constructs as well.
Okay, let's kick over to a demo.
So I'm going to start with a GitHub repo.
So this is our Rezonant product brain with some anonymization on top of it.
Because it's kind of cool
that it has customer data or conversations in it at least.
So you can see here we've got a bunch of different forms of inputs.
And we can see if we look at linear for we've got a bunch of linear tickets.
These are all the linear tickets that were updated since its last run.
It typically runs on a daily basis.
And the structure here is pretty simple.
You've got inputs that process daily.
You've got sources. That is the raw data.
We don't keep all the raw data because sometimes it can overwhelm the agent.
And then you've got wiki
which consists of customer insight features, product principles,
which is trying to express this
higher level of how do you have taste and coherency in a system,
and then technical context which expresses our front end flows.
So other things, we've got an input.
We've got granola session that we ran on Friday.
And then you can also add a bunch of manual information.
And lastly we've got a bunch of GitHub diffs in here as well
which are going to get processed by our system now because this takes
a little bit of time to process, probably longer than I have, unfortunately.
I'll show you what it did so we can see here.
It's gone through all of those tickets.
It's updated a bunch of the different kind of feature level context files
that we've got, as well as this like technical contents, front end
features, which describes all of our front end flows, end to end.
And you can see the final processed
state is it's moved a ton of stuff out of inputs.
That's it's kind of input queue.
And then it has done things like we moved our JIRA
authentication to no longer be team scoped, but OAuth scoped.
It's understood that and express that in a way
that can then be used by the agent going forward.
And we can see it's done a bunch more kind of synthesis here
across our front end features, which is our UX flows.
So that's the core is this kind of brain that can take inputs over time.
But now I want to show you an end to end demo.
So in order to do this
I need to just give you a tiny bit of context on Rezonant itself.
Resonant is a product workspace.
This is our home page.
It allows you to create PRD specs tickets and then ship them to coding agents
very quickly.
And we have this product
charter feature here, which I'm going to write a ticket for in a second.
This is what our kind of main page looks like.
So you can see here I've got a PRD about a new feature
we're working on, and a set of tasks that I can then send to coding agents.
But our main product interface for agents and humans is actually slack.
So we try to avoid anybody having to go into these systems
unless it's very direct to the task that they're trying to accomplish.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to kick off a linear ticket.
Let's imagine this was reported by the customer.
And I'm just going to select my ticket context.
So product charter confusion is the kind of feedback.
And it says here can never be read that actually it's a bit fuzzy.
Hey let me see if I can make it a bit bigger.
That doesn't seem to be. I've got much better.
I'll try and explain it anyway.
So it says users are confused about the product
charter feature shown on the home page.
They don't understand what it is
and have no way to get to see it or understand it better.
So I'm just going to submit this as our first ticket, and the system will
then operate on top of that.
Now I'm going to create a second linear ticket here.
And this one instead is going to be a bit more complicated.
So the idea here is that people want to be able to estimate
the size of the task before the agent actually get started.
And there's a description here of basically, you know what that means.
The process of story pointing essentially
is a kind of common feature request that we've had within Rezonant.
I'm just going to make sure this is labeled and kick this off.
So these tickets on the surface they're both kind of feature requests.
But what the agent should do if it understands my product
brain correctly is different actions as a consequence.
And so what we can see over here in the Rezonant chat.
So I cheated a little bit on this first one.
Just because I need something
to show you in the kind of coding task takes a little bit of time, is
Rezonant has pinged me here with a question about the product
charter confusion on the start page.
So because it's understood a whole bunch of context here
about our product and exactly how it works,
it's made a recommendation and it thinks that this is well specified enough
that it can actually go all the way through to implementation.
So you can see it's presented me with two options.
The first is ship a quick fix here, and the second is
fold it into the onboarding work that Rob is working on more generally.
And it's asking me, what do I want to do about that? Right.
So I've responded here and I've said, yeah,
let's implement the narrow fix that you suggested.
And then it has come back to me here and said
that it's posted its recommendation on this comment.
So let's click in here and have a look at that.
And we can see
here that it's got the recommendation to pursue the fix well documented, but
it's actually created the task in Rezonant and sent it to a coding agent.
So it's really gone all the way through there, but made sure
that it has solicited my opinion on how to do the kind of
coherency and strategy within our product before going there.
Okay, so if we have a look at this,
we can see here that we've got this product charter
chip task and Apr associated with it
and that that has completed the work end to end.
So obviously here you would then want an engineer to check it before
it submitted, but it's really trying to do a full autonomous PM workflow there. Now
the other thing
that it can do is when it sees that there is a ticket,
it will actually ping me with a different recommendation about this
kind of second ticket that we were just looking at.
So you can see here for the task complexity estimator what it's done.
Instead, if we have a look at its reply, is
it has not recommended that this goes straight to agent coding.
What it has recommended instead is that we write a PRD for this.
And I've given it a bit of guidance here.
So I've said, yeah, let's do that.
Here's here's what it said.
Strategically, it's a strong yes,
but it also overlaps with some other work that we are doing.
And it wants to write a short PRD up before proceeding.
And I've said you should do that.
But the important thing to understand here is that when we talk about
task complexity and story pointing, that is extremely individual per customer.
And so you need a way to tackle that as a fundamental part of the work.
So then it's again
kind of gone through the same process here, posted its recommendation.
And we can take a look at that.
Okay.
So there's a PRD.
And if we take a look
at what it's done here we can see
why should we pursue.
It reduces the ambiguity a bunch of things that explains
how it relates to a strategic work, explains a bunch of kind of related work,
and then also starts to try and understand
this kind of piece of complexity, understanding work that I had asked it to.
So that's really kind of how a product brain can
then really superpower a set of workflows.
Now also, what should of course happen is it should feed that work
finally back to the product brain itself.
So hopefully if we refresh here we can see there's product charter confusion.
Work has populated an input session that then the next time product brain work
runs will read that and it will improve the way it thinks about product work
going forward.
So you get a full cycle experience.
All right.
So you can build this yourself.
We critically use a GitHub repo to back this system,
because it means your engineers can also provide it with their own forms of input,
as well as the kind of inputs that we've shown today.
Working with a bunch of companies as well to think
about how to do this for different size of orgs.
I think if folks are familiar with OpenClaw, OpenClaw has a lot of
the same concepts, but actually configuring how you think about privacy,
the different MCP connectors that you want,
how you want to organize for teams, etc., and then how you want to tweak that over
time is the expertise that we have built up with a number of our design partners.
All right.
If you want to talk about this, this is a QR code.
I respond to every email.
We've also got a booth here that we can chat at.
But yeah, we'd love to take any questions that you've got.
I think I've managed to actually go ahead of time.
There's going to be a lot of questions.
So can we get a mic?
Just a couple of questions down the front here.
Got one over here and then one over here.
Sure. There'll be more after that.
Oh. Thank. You for your presentation.
Talking about privacy.
One thing that maybe it's not managing representation.
What about when a client ask you where my data is going?
Whenever you share with LLMs, like Afrobeat or
any models that you have behind.
Yeah.
So the the brain repo that
we have lives very much in customers domain.
It's not our repo. I mean this is our repo, right.
Because it's our company.
But for the design partners we've got it lives in their repo.
So from a privacy perspective, all the fundamental data there is
is stored
there in terms of like actually sending that conversation to LLMs for indexing.
Yes. You would have to reveal that as part of your kind of like third party
processing agreement or do an anonymization system.
So like if you look at our product brain, for example, that I've got here,
I'm nominally going to show you all of our like customer data,
except that like it goes through an anonymization process before it gets here.
Right?
So if you've got that plus a mapping that owning your team can see,
then none of that system is actually
sending data to Anthropic that they don't that they can do anything with.
If you see what.
Thanks for the presentation in the demo.
I'm myself.
You mentioned briefly that you use GitHub as a base
so you can actually connect with developers nicely.
Could you elaborate on the ways how developers then use the outputs?
Put in a git repo? Yes.
And yeah.
How it's like from the lifecycle perspective,
how it mentions the responsibilities between PM and developer.
Yeah.
So there's a couple of ways that developers can interact with this.
The first is our inputs have a manual folder.
Doesn't have anything in it right now because
we haven't processed anything manually.
But if a developer wants to put something in manually, they can do so.
But they can also just treat this like a normal GitHub repo, right?
So they can pull it down from their GitHub org and then interact it using whatever
coding agent of their choice
to then ensure that they can move faster from a coding perspective.
So I mean, like if they have the linear issue
and it references the the documents within that
repo, how it should look like from the developer standpoint.
Yeah.
So it really depends on there is no kind of one size fits
all with building the kind of system that allows flexibility
for different workflows and different kind of waves of engaging with it.
And so what we do with design partners is really trying to understand, like,
what are the initial workflows that would add a ton of value
but are also getting towards this like spectrum of autonomy.
And so the question kind of depends a bit on like,
how are they working, what are their core artifacts and that kind of thing.
So it's difficult to answer
kind of in the abstract, but hopefully that can seem a bit.
Of a step.
And the quick follow up, does it mean that ultimately you nudge
product managers to put their documents into the GitHub
instead of like Google Docs, so developers can actually access
and like grounder agents to what they are building for? Yes.
Yeah, that's that's
kind of a core concept of resonance, is that there's a lot of context
that's useful for coding agents that is currently kept in things
like Google Docs, which now to us anyway feel very backwards.
But, you know, you could in theory,
I don't think has an MCP connector that's super easy to use.
But yeah, you could ingest via MCP as well if you wanted to.
Thank you.
It's okay.
So the like all all the time
like like the input you are showing, they're like user stories.
They will probably build on on on each other relate and so on.
So which actually would require that you have to kind of refactor
your input to give like the current state of a user stories
or any ideas on on how how you work on this.
Yeah. So it does do that automatically.
So everything that's in the wiki, for example,
is very specific
in terms of the underlying tickets that it referenced.
Let me just see if I can find one here.
So you can see here there's a bunch of like linear references.
And as it goes through it will see it will basically do it
the same way as you do a diff of the GitHub.
It will do a diff of the linear to understand how stuff has progressed,
and then feed that into the wiki as appropriate.
Hi Emma.
Christ as.
Lord I think every product.
Manager has a love hate relationship with product
management tools and have done for the best however many years.
Do you see a world with Rezonant
where you're abstracting the need for them to interact with one of those tools?
So it's largely through an agent? Or do you?
Do you still see a UI interface for them in terms of how they do their job?
Yeah, I think that the tooling that you will need going forward is
more about like maintaining your strategy, maintaining your kind of product
principles, the necessarily like managing a lot of the tickets.
And I think the transition that a lot of AI native
teams have gone through already is that a ticket
is basically a full feature now, rather than something which is like,
you know, broken out into your front end and your back end and that kind of thing.
But yeah, I don't know.
We'll see how we'll see how far people, people push out.
Thank
you for the overview from the stuff that we work on.
A lot of it is compliance related and regulatory,
and therefore we have to be very specific with what we do.
How do you manage ownership of the
PRD, or the work that's put forward by the agents,
and ensuring that it is checked by a person
so that you can later on say, okay, this has been checked by a person
and we made a mistake versus the agent just came up with it.
Yeah, I mean, I think that's why the workflows have to be configurable
and also why we think this like agent human interface is very important
so that if you're running in a more regulatory domain, you can say
like it's never the case, for example, that an agent can write the code
without some kind of a documentation first, for example,
and that you can also build
an approval flows and that kind of thing which are actually documented.
I mean, in some ways it is an approval flow.
When there is a PR and you move it forward to the next layer.
But obviously as to whether or not people have like really read the PRD, I mean,
it depends on the underlying company
and how how good people are at meeting their compliance
goals, I guess.
Hi. Yeah.
You presented this sort of evolution of the PM role, and even there
you had the agent automatically creating code off the back of it.
So it seems like the line between PM and engineer blurring now.
And so where do you sort of see that going actually.
Yeah I mean I think the
there's two directions that this seems to be heading.
One is that you end up with this kind of product builder role,
which is PMS moving down, and then you are also ending up
with PMS moving up, which is they move into a much more of a focus
kind of GM and strategy role.
I don't think that necessarily companies will there'll be one
winner in the short term,
I think from like a Stripe perspective and a Google perspective.
For example, they've always run more as PMS, being GM
type roles anyway, and this will only kind of accentuate that.
And so if I had a prediction, it's probably more that way.
And you'll see engineers moving more into kind of the product builder type
type roles.
But I think a lot of experimentation is also happening right now.
Thanks for the talk.
It's been really interesting.
I can see how this would be a great tool for a greenfield project.
Team or company,
but how would an existing company with millions of lines of code
or documents all across confluence or something like that?
How would they how would you ingest that information at scale?
And wouldn't that be hugely costly?
Yeah.
So in terms of kind of the typical rollout.
So a company
typically starts with like a team kind of seeing what this looks like.
Right.
And one of the most important things about kind of
I think deploying this kind of product brain infrastructure into a company
is understanding, like, okay, how are their teams actually laid out
and how are you going to ingest data over time in a way
that kind of scales with the rate of change?
And really every product brain needs to look a little bit
different for the company for the rate of change of data.
And then it needs to be managed to their cost parameters.
So what we are aiming to do through the kind of design
partnerships we've got is understand how much consistency there is,
so that you can actually have a system that helps to initialize a product brain
without us having to spend a lot of time consulting on it, essentially,
because there's a lot of different ways
that companies are structured and that kind of thing.
So yeah, I think it's for us, it's an art right now
that we want to turn into a science, well, a codified science ideally.
Are there any further questions?
Oh, we've got one over here.
In terms of the workflow.
Does resonance send this straight into the agent to start coding
or Eagle straight to egleston human face before coding actually starts.
So the way that our product brain works is it uses the Rezonant
API to actually create those coding agent jobs.
And then that creates PRS on top of main, which are then reviewed by a human.
So that's how that's how I work.
But different people do at different ways.
Okay. I think that's all the questions.
Emma, thank you ever so much for a fantastic job.
Up next we have